Hsiao Guei ( literally " raising child ghosts " ) :
A folk practice prevalent in Chinese societies ,
whereby dead fetuses are worshipped in urns ,
and fed with the blood of their master .
Child ghosts possess great power to bring their master fortune .
Some are so powerful they can even be used to kill .
But for such dark arts , a price must be paid ...
Mr. Yang ,
the total land area measures 7000 square feet .
The house itself is 2600 squarefeet .
It 's all in the document .
Do you want to double-check ?
How old is this house ?
Seventy to eighty years .
Sounds about right ,
from the Japanese occupation period ?
You research buildings ?
I 'm an architect .
I never heard anything about this house .
Mr. Yang ,
you spent most of your life in England
so you don 't know about your distant relatives here .
What is their relationship to me ?
Why would they leave me this house ?
Uh ... your family history is complicated .
I 'll have to check the records .
Young people aren 't used to old houses .
The best thing to do is to sell it .
I rather like old houses .
You don 't see these carvings
in modern architecture anymore .
The Department of Culture maybe interested in the house .
Besides , it 's too big for one person to live in .
I strongly suggest you sell it .
Don 't worry , I won 't live alone .
You have a wife ?
Soon .
Congratulations then .
Five shows in three days , I 'm exhausted .
Now l can finally rest .
Don 't they want you back for the next show ?
I don 't want to do it .
I have enough problems to deal with .
I have to think about it .
What problems ?
Like where to live , my rent 's up .
Just move in with James , he just inherited a house .
So it 's real ?
When you phoned me , I thought you just
made up an excuse to come see my performance .
Of course I 'm here for you , but also to inherit the house .
Where is the house ? In Taipei ?
No , just outside the city , not too far .
You 're not going to sell it ?
Not for now .
What 's next ?
A car , a house ,
Do I hear wedding bells ?
I 'm thinking about it .
Don 't kid around ,
I 'm planning to study abroad .
You want to go abroad again ?
Yeah ,
I 'm seriously considering .
I just returned , and you 're leaving .
What 's going to happen to us ?
Didn 't we agree not to talk about this ?
Why are you bringing it up now ?
Before you go abroad ,
Shouldn 't we make a decision ?
What decision ?
Why are you asking me again ?
What if something happens while I 'm away ?
I just want your commitment .
I 'm leaving .
Don 't take it too seriously .
No , I am serious .
Yo
I 'm not trying to limit you .
I just want your promise ,
just one word .
Thanks .
Are you all right ?
I 'm fine .
Put that upstairs , thanks .
What time is your flight ?
Do you want me to accompany you ?
Have you packed your things ?
I brought everything here .
Let me take you to the airport then .
You don 't have to .
It 's ok , I can drive you .
We won 't see each other again for some time .
It 's really not necessary .
I 've decided to do the next show .
I 'll stay in Taiwan for a while .
Should I move your things over tomorrow ?
Uh , all right .
This house is so big ,
what are you going to do with it ?
I don 't know yet .
Let 's just move in for now .
Yeah , it 's a little bit messy .
But don 't worry , we 'll clean it up slowly .
What 's on this floor ?
Looks like a family shrine .
It 's so high up .
What 's up there ?
I don 't know , should betheattic .
Can we go up there ?
Better not , it looks dangerous .
Things look fine between you two again .
Not really , she hasn 't made up her mind yet .
The boys are drinking too much , eh ?
It 's a special night , as long as they 're happy .
Your house is really enormous .
Yeah , I guess I 'll get used to it .
So you 're really going to settle here ?
It 's hard to say .
Your house is so antique .
I 'll doa news article on it .
Ok , I don 't mind .
How long have you stopped dancing ?
So long .
What 's upstairs ?
I don 't know , we don 't use it anyway .
Let 's go take a look ?
No , it 's scary .
Then I must see for sure .
What 's inside here ?
The old family shrine .
The style is so different from downstairs .
Let 's go
Just let me take a look .
There 's nothing to see .
Don 'tworry .
You know ?
I 'm working on a story about unnatural feng shui
but I 've never seen a shrine with this many photos before .
Don 't do that .
Don 't worry .
Are you done ?
So strange .
All right , let 's go .
Come over here .
What ?
Haveyou guys been here recently ?
What 's this ?
You 're freaking me out , let 's go .
Let 's go , hurry
Ok , let 's start from the top , ready
and seven , eight , one two three , turn right ...
Ok , hold .
Good .
Still waiting for your friend ? Bye bye .
Hi , this is Yi-Chen 's mobile , please leave a message .
Did youfind her ?
She 's never stood me up before .
I 'm worried something happened to her .
Don 't be silly .
Maybe something came up and she couldn 't reach you
Why don 't you rest ...
Impossible , she 'salways punctual .
She used to be a dancer .
I 've known her for so many years . She 'd call me if something came up .
People change
Like Cheng , he never used to smoke and drink ,
but the year he left Taiwan , he changed
James , could you get my clothes .
James !
James ...
The foot prints have gone .
Yi-Chen !
What are you doing ?
Yo
Why are you here ?
I was ... I 've been looking for you .
Where did you go all night ?
I was ...
Let her sit down first , I 'll get some water .
What happened ,
tell me .
What happened to you ?
I was at ...
What ?
Cheng !
You don 't remember what happened in between ?
I really don 't remember ...
I just remember ,
I was already late when I left .
Then I got on the taxi ,
and then I lost all memory ...
How did you get here ?
I don 't know
As soon as I opened my eyes , I was here .
Cheng , how did you get in my house last night ?
What is going on ?
Your turn , man .
Of course .
Don 't drink too much .
Nobody can beat me , I used to be on the school team .
Just play .
Cheng , you want some water ?
What are you doing ? You want some water ?
Cheng
Cut it out !
Hey ! Cheng
" Chang Yi-Chen "
Hello ?
It 's me , I have something to ask you .
What time is your last memory yesterday night ?
And do you know how James inherited the house ?
I don 't really know , he never explained .
Besides , I 'm off to Kaohsiung on business
But I ...
Look , I 'll call you when I 'm back in Taipei .
James !
... someone 's down there .
James
Go take a look !
Why aren 't you in bed , did I wake you ?
You 're here ...
What ?
Upstairs ...
Yi-Chen !
What are you doing here ?
How did you get in ?
Hello
It 's ok , I 'm right here
Yes , it 's me . What is it ?
Don 't cry
What ?
Yes , yes .
What ? Cheng is dead ?
When did this happen ?
I 'll walk you out .
What 's the situation ?
No rope has been found ,
or any other possible weapon .
Nothing 's been touched
except for this bathroom .
What does the coroner say ?
He says that the mark around the neck
tilts upwards
so it means suicide by hanging
Suicide by hanging ?
Could also be hung to death by someone else .
Find the victim 's phone transmission reports .
What 's going on ?
This is Detective Wu .
He 's in charge of Cheng 's case .
This is my fiancee , Yo .
What 's he doing here ?
I 'm investigating Liu Tin-Cheng 's death .
I 'm here to find out about Chang Yi-Chen
Yi-Chen ? What does this have to do with her ?
Here are some files
I found from the hospital and from Liu 's family
Miss Chang is the last person to contact the deceased ,
but we haven 't been able to locate her all day .
I have to go back to the bureau .
I 'll stop by again later .
Bye for now .
I 'll see you out .
And three and four ... and eight ...
Yo , don 't make your arms so stiff ,
or your partner can 't hold you up , ok ?
The rest of you , take a break .
Yo , come over here .
What 's wrong with you today ?
Your performance is terrible , are you ill ?
No , I just need some rest and I 'll be ok .
A few more days until the show , stay focused .
I understand .
Sorry , I 've been busy at the bureau all day .
I had no time to eat yet .
You guys have some too .
No , we 're fine .
Mr. Yang , you told me on the phone
that Liu and Chang have been sneaking
into your house recently ?
It 's not " sneaking in " .
It 's complicated , she doesn 't know what she 's doing .
She told you that , or you 're just assuming ?
She looks like she doesn 't know .
Looks like ? It can 't be that simple
What do you want to hear ?
I don 't mean to offend you ,
but don 't you find this all very strange ?
Indeed , these recent happenings are so strange ,
we 're even beginning to suspect ...
if there are " things " .
You mean " ghosts " ?
I don 't believe them .
I have a simple solution ,
but I need your cooperation .
Miss Chang
is the key suspect in Liu 's case .
I must find her .
What can we do ? We 'll cooperate .
I 'll stay for the night .
I believe she 'll come back tonight .
Mr. Yang , believe me .
The stranger people behave ,
the greater the secret .
All the doors and windows on the first floor are closed .
Did you check upstairs ?
Yes , before coming down .
Any sign of her ?
No .
Can I go have a look ?
Please .
Please
Yi-Chen !
You 're here again ...
Jay , Jay !
Where did you come from ?
Where the hell were you ?
Didn 't I order you to guard the front door ?
I did , nobody 's entered .
Go find out Liu 's time of death for me .
Hurry !
Right away .
What ?
Where 's Detective Wu ?
I don 't know , wasn 't he just here ?
I 'll take a taxi home by myself .
Sorry for bothering you these past few days .
But It 's already so late , I 'm worried .
I 'll call you when I get home .
Maybe I should ...
You scared us !
Did you walk past the study ?
No .
Did you hear the strange noises ?
What noises ?
What is that ?
The door 's jammed !
Jammed ?
There 's something inside .
Don 't scare me .
isthere ?
I was at the police station .
Impossible .
There 's definitely something wrong with this house .
Are you better , or do you still feel ill ?
Do you want me to get some water ?
Yo .
What is it ?
Nothing .
Don 't dwell on what 's happened the past few days .
it must have someway .
Let 's go .
Close the door .
Front entrance monitor is fine , turn it on .
Which channel on the radio do we use ?
Channel two .
Ok , first floor is set .
Tilt the monitor on the second floor higher up .
Ok , adjusting now .
Hi , It 's me .
I have something to tell you .
Come to my news station tonight .
Hurry !
Crime .
Should be here .
Here , hold this .
Let me show you .
This article is from twenty years ago .
Mass Suicide at Millionaire Household . Only one be survivor .
Isn 't this our house ?
What is this ?
Does James know his relatives all died the same night ?
I don 't think so .
He never said anything .
Oh , there 's another article .
Here .
Thisarticlesays
that a thief who stole from your house .
Hung to death three days later .
Yes , in your house .
And his family said that
he didn 't dare sleep for three days straight
Why not ?
Because as soon as he fell asleep ,
hewouldwake upinthathouseagain .
Yo
We saw these spots on the floor .
We walked in and saw a body
James was home alone , I didn 't know who it was .
Then You touched the body .
That 's what happened .
Weird .
What ?
How come the screen goes fuzzy every time he walks by ?
Don 't scare me , must be coincidence .
Rewind it .
Hello ?
You must be kidding ?
Ok , we 'll go check it out .
Found them ?
Yeah .
So , what 's the situation ?
From the look of the wound , It 's a tear .
not a cut .
the force that did it is exceptionally powerful .
Iike what ?
Iike being pulled apart by a horse .
Gain fortune through evil ; fall into endless hell .
Miss , this prophecy is for you .
James !
I gotta go to work .
We need to talk .
Can we do it later ?
No , this is very important .
Let 's move , ok ?
Don 't you think the house is haunted ?
And we 're living here !
Yo
I know things have been weird recently , and you 're worried .
But so far it 's only happened to other people .
The two of us are fine , nothing wrong .
Don 't think too much .
But so many things have already happened !
Hello , hold on ...
Yo , I gotta go .
We 'll talk later .
All right , I promise you .
As soon as my job is secure , we 'll find a new place to live .
I 'll be right there , bye .
The Medical Record of Cheng-Yang asylum .
Mr. Ma ,
I 'm James Yang 's fiancee .
I have something to ask you .
It 's about the Yang family .
Hello ? Yes , please hold .
Mr. Ma , it 's for you .
Please tell her to hold .
Please hold .
Prepare Mr.Wang 's files for me .
Ok .
Hello ? Yesyesyes .
Yes , I found it , Mrs. Yang .
Yes , she was the one who survived .
Waiver of inheritance . Signed : Sue Yang
She 's waiting for you over there .
She 's pretty stable today , you can talk to her .
I have something else to do .
Thank you .
Good morning , Aunt .
My name is Yo .
Sorry to bother you .
Do you remember James Yang ?
I 'm his fiancee .
James is back in Taiwan ?
How is he ?
Don 't go back to that house !
But ...
We 're living in that house now .
I always thought it was just a cat .
What is it ?
Be good , Sue , I have to feed the cat .
You go back to your room .
Nanny will play with you later .
I want to play with the cat too .
No , Sue cannot play with the cat .
Why not ?
The cat is still wild .
You can play with it when you 're older .
Be a good girl and go back to your room .
I should 've known it wasn 't a cat .
That was just a name for it .
What our family raised were ghosts .
The so called Hsiao-guei .
it started many generations ago , I don 't know when .
Our ancestors believed that child ghosts bring fortune .
So they bought dead babies in the black market ,
and then forced family members to feed it with blood .
Through this feeding ritual the child ghost found its master ,
and was controlled by the family .
No !
These ghosts obeyed orders and brought prosperity .
Sometimes they even helped us eliminate our enemies .
Generation after generation ,
our family made fortune through this dark practice .
Finally , there was a price to pay .
What price ?
Can 't you guess from this asylum ?
Eventually , our family 's children were born
either handicapped or terminally ill .
Only one or two were healthy enough to live .
in orderto protect the healthy few ,
the unhealthy ones were sent to asylums
or locked up inside the house .
Later , to maintain the family fortune ,
our elders made an even crueler decision .
The unhealthy children were forced to do the feeding ,
while the healthy ones inherited the fortune .
This way , it 's all kept within the family .
The ones who sacrifice , and the ones who benefit .
And the secret will forever be hidden within the Yangs .
it worked out pretty well until my generation ,
until my twin sister and l .
When I was five ,
I was detected with chronic brain tumor .
I was locked up in the attic on the fourth floor .
And your sister ?
She was the healthy one .
She grew up loved by the elders .
The appointed heiress .
who found a husband , and prepared to give an offspring .
But who would 've thought ?
when I was eighteen years old , that year .
What horror !
I could hear her howling all the way up in the attic
The whole night .
Even now it gives me nightmares .
what happened ?
I didn 't know at the time .
I just kept on listening ,
and waiting .
A week later , I learnt the truth .
The truth ?
My twin sister fell ill all of a sudden .
she was apparently infected during labor ,
and her body was no good anymore .
That same year ,
my brain tumor miraculously disappeared .
And from that moment ,
our fates switched .
I was released
while my sister was thrown into the attic .
She could not understand
why she lost everything just because of her health .
she wouldn 't accept her fate .
She couldn 't even see her child again .
Your sister 's child ?
James .
The only son and heir in three generations .
When I saw his innocent little face ,
I realized that our family curse should not continue .
So I did my best to send him overseas .
Thank goodness , he escaped the peril twenty years ago .
What actually happened twenty years ago ?
My sister cut her wrist and released all her blood
She fed it to the ghost and used its force
to hang the whole family to death .
Maybe because
I went through what she went through ,
she spared my life .
When the police later interrogated me ,
I told them that my sister had gone crazy .
There was a thunderstorm that night .
All fifteen members of our family ,
were hung to death at the same time , same place ,
and the same height above the ground .
My sister killed herself right after .
Midnight , at exactly midnight .
This can 't be true .
But one thing I don 't understand ...
Why did she do this ?
I understand her pain
Because all those years locked in the attic ,
I could only think of one thing ...
to be free .
I believe the ghost
is still hidden in the attic .
You must think of a way to leave .
help James .
Before a new family forms ,
get out of there !
Aunt
I have something to tell you .
Don 't move , I 'll save you .
Why are you here ?
Are you all right ?
What is this ?
This place is for worshipping child spirits .
It would be good to keep it here .
I just want to get this over with .
These spirits don 't mean any harm .
Some of them were too young to even have a name
before they were sent here .
How can we get rid of it ?
You can 't get rid of karma .
Some parents bring dead children here
thinking it would wipe away their guilt .
But in actual fact , the guilt never goes away .
After all , it was a human life that was sacrificed .
I would like to keep this here at your temple .
How long have you raised it ?
It 's not my doing .
It was a long time ago , left by the family .
So be it .
I 'll take this child ghost .
it can stay over there .
Thank you
Don 't worry , Buddha will take care of it .
Young man , go home and live sincerely .
Thank you .
It 's time to board , you guys should go .
You take care .
Don 't worry about us .
What are you going to do ?
Sell the house first .
Find a new place and start over .
That would be good .
I 'm sorry .
Becareful .
I will , you too .
I 'm going in , you guys can go .
I 'll call youwhen I land .
Miss Chang Yi-Chen
Please proceed to gate 15
Your flight is about to depart .
I 'll look over here , you look over there
Miss Chang Yi-Chen
Please proceed to gate 15
Your flight is about to depart .
Did youfind her ?
No , everyone 's gone .
Something 's happened to her .
Calm down , I 'll try her mobile .
I just did .
What is it ?
Yi-Chen !
Get her down !
Didn 't I tell you to get her down ?
Why didn 't you save her ?
But there was no rope , there was no rope up there !
Yi-Chen , please don 't die !
Anybody out there ?
Please help ! Help !
Sister ...
My dear sister ...
You are the heir to the Yang family .
You must sacrifice all to protect your family .
The ghost 's power will help you .
Remember , you are the heir .
The only heir to the family .
Nobody can stop you from what you want .
Beware of all those who are not of the Yang family .
It 's power enables us to help you .
Remember , we are of the same family .
Hello , Miss Hsu ?
I am calling from Cheng-Yang asylum .
Uh ... I 'm sorry to tell you
James Yang 's aunt passed away suddenly
Could you come please ?
Auntie
I have something to tell you .
I 'm pregnant .
Come .
There 's a wooden ledge over there .
Push it up push .
James , it 's Mommy .
James , look ...
Come quickly ! Stop her !
James , it 's Mommy !
I 'm your Mommy !
Please let me see my child !
Please !
I beg you !
I 'm your Mommy !
James , look at me ! Look at me !
What are you doing ?
What are you doing to my child ? No !
Don 't hurt my child ! Please don 't !
Don 't hurt my child !
Give him back to me ! Give him back !
My son !
You are the heir to the Yang family .
You must sacrifice all to protect your family .
The ghost 's power will help you .
Mister , are you all right ?
Where are you going ?
Where are you going ... ?
Yo !
Yo ?
James
Why are you ... ?
Why am I here ?
What was that ?
That was my mother .
What do you mean ?
I admit ...
everything that happened here recently
has something to do with me .
When I was young , they took me away from here .
Since then , every night ,
I dreamt that I would come back .
After we moved in ,
I started remembering my childhood .
I tried to free my mother ,
but I caused her death instead .
Is she responsible for Cheng and Yi-Chen 's deaths ?
If you knew , why didn 't you say anything ?
I don 't know why I didn 't dare tell you .
At first , all I wanted was to keep you here with me .
I want to be with you forever .
I was wrong , it 's my fault .
None of this should not have happened .
You should go , you need to get out of here .
Go !
I am not going to go .
It 's too late .
Everything 's too late .
James , I 'm part of the family now .
I 'm pregnant with your child .
I can 't leave anymore .
Listen to me , I 'll be safe .
Don 't worry ,
we 'll find a way .
Why did this happen ?
Why is this happening ?
I 've made up my mind already ,
to be with you forever .
Nobody will separate us .
Yo !
You are the only heir to the Yang family .
Remember , use the ghost 's power .
It can help you make the family stronger .
Frogive me .
No ... I 'm sorry .
Good afternoon , I 'm from Chungshan Precinct .
Miss Hsu Hsiao-yo
You have been unconscious for three days .
We need you to answer a few questions .
Doyou remember what happened ?
Ok , let me ask you this ,
Did your fiancee assault you ?
Yo .
My dream has always been to have a family together with you .
But I never imagined that I 'd put you in danger .
So I 'm going to put an end to it now .
I 'm going to set you free .
Just bear with it .
It 'll be over soon
Forgive me .
Can you hear me ? Miss Hsu ?
Are you all right ?
I 'm sorry , but I really need you to answer some questions .
Miss Hsu .
Did you find his body ?
Yes
Mr. Yang cut his wrist and died right next to you .
We 're sorry about that .
But the importantthing is ...
you 've managed to keep your baby .